# CHRISTOPHER POENARU

COMPUTER ENGINEER - FUNCTIONAL PROGRAMMER - TRIATHLETE - ROCK CLIMBER

# **SKILLS**

Scala

Go

Haskell

Java

AWS + Heroku

**Postgres** 

Redis

Cassandra

MongoDB

# **PROJECTS**

#### **SCRAVA**

**☑** KIAMBOGO/SCRAVA

 Community recognized, opensource Scala client for the Strava API

### **ROAD QUALITY**

**☑** TRIFECTALABS/ROADQUALITY

- Crowdsourced road quality and traffic safety data for cyclists
- Allows cyclists to rate sections of a road or path to build a community driven topology of the safest cycling routes
- API and pathing logic implemented in Scala; custom mapping engine built with Rust

# CONTACT

kiambogo@gmail.com

🗥 chrispoenaru.com

in chrispoenaru

() kiambogo

# **ABOUT**

Computer engineer with **5+ years experience designing, implementing**, and **owning** high-performance, **back-end** software and distributed systems. Cultivates a rich understanding of multiple layers of computer systems, from high-level applications and **database performance tuning**, to **infrastructure**, **networking**, and **security**.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **MASONHUB**

Los Angeles, CA (Remote)

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

Jan. 2019 - Jan. 2021

- Third engineer at a fast paced 3PL startup; responsible for designing, building, and owning multiple core systems that scaled the company from 0 clients to 35+ within 2 years
- Spearheaded Shopify integration, providing real-time inventory levels and ingesting customer orders for fulfillment
- Architected fault-tolerant, horizontally scalable printer management system allowing for custom supply chain document creation. Successfully printed over 250,000+ documents
- Refactored critical, production database schema improving average inventory ledger query times by 90% and bulk order processing time by 75%

# **HUDSON'S BAY COMPANY**

New York, NY (Remote) Aug. 2018 - Jan. 2019

**LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

- Engineering lead of a team of 4 intermediate and senior level developers
- Directed team towards adopting a functional code base with Scala Cats + FS2
- Architected a multi-service initiative to optimize safety stock levels and reduce order shorting

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Nov. 2017 - Aug. 2018

 Conflated inventory management systems across banners as part of the shared selling initiative, driving double-digit growth for the Gilt banner

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2016 - Nov. 2017

- Refactored mission critical service to use Postgres instead of Mongo; strategized deployment resulting in zero downtime
- Modified website delivery window calculation to include customer location, improving checkout conversion across many US states

STRAVA

San Francisco, CA Aug. 2015 - Dec. 2015

PLATFORM ENGINEER INTERN

- Optimized user characteristics processing with development of Scala service leveraging Spark
- Designed and deployed Spark cluster to production atop of Apache Mesos

# **EDUCATION**

## **UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO**

Waterloo, Canada

**BASC. COMPUTER ENGINEERING** 

2011-2016